Guide to the Cornell University Crew records, 1871-2013.
Cornell University Crew records, 1871-2013.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Crew records, 1871-2013.
40-1-924
Cornell Crew (Rowing team)
11.7 cubic ft., 178,913,890 bytes (170.6 MB)
Rosters, diary, journals, scrapbooks, logs, map, correspondence, programs, photographs, glass negatives, slides, videocassettes, and film.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes varsity and freshman crew ephemera and photographs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Cornell Crew was also referred to as the Cornell Navy, or rowing team, but should not be called the crew team.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes varsity and freshman crew rosters; Coach Charles Courtney's diary and journals of distances rowed, weather conditions, and other information; newspaper clippings and other press; regatta programs; scrapbooks; map; correspondence with Todd Jesdale; minutes of the Sprague Boat Club; photographs, photograph albums, and glass negatives of crew events, Ithaca, New York views, and the Cayuga Lake Inlet; and a phonograph record and cassette copy concerning a 1946 regatta at Lake Washington. Material pertaining to John L. Collyer and Donald E. Maclay. Also, videocassettes and a film of the 1957 Cornell crew victory at Henley. Also, the crew logs (1937-1970) and crew files (1937-1975) of coach R. Harrison "Stork" Sanford; and slides of crews and crew activities. Also, scrapbooks (1896-1898). Also some film including footage of the 1929 Syracuse vs Cornell regatta by Allan H. Mogensen. 1957 Henley regatta materials.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Crew (Rowing team); Collyer, John L.; Courtney, Charles.; Jesdale, Todd.; Maclay, Donald E.; Sanford, R. Harrison "Stork."; Cornell University--Athletics.; Sprague Boat Club.; Henley Royal Regatta
Subjects:
Regattas.; Rowing.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.); Cayuga Lake.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Negatives.; Journals.; Maps.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Due to the fragility and potential degradation of moving image and sound recordings, viewing and listening is limited to items that have been digitized. If an item is in another media format, you may request to have the item digitized for access. Information on ordering access copies may be found on our Reproductions and Permissions page.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also Ernest William Schoder papers, #16-4-1156 for an additional film.
See also Arthur Charles Stallman papers, #2981 for a 1927 photo album featuring the crew.
SERIES LIST
Series I. General files
Boxes 1, 8, 9, 11, 12, 15-18, 22, 23, 27, 28 and Mapcase Folder 6, 7
Series II. Audio and visual material
Box 7 and other individually located items
Series III. Photographs
Boxes 2-7, 10, 12-14, 18-26, Mapcase Folders 1-5 and 7
Series IV. Objects
Box 17 and loose items
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General files
  - Freshman crew candidates (Box 1)
    Includes dates 1904-1905, 1908-1910, 1912
  - Varsity crew candidates (Box 1)
    Includes dates 1902, 1907-1909
  - Correspondence, 1948-1970; Scrapbooks, 1931-1932, 1940; Courtney's log book, 1911-1920 (Box 8)
  - Coach Sanford's crew logs, 1937-1970, and files, 1937-1975 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 11)
  - Two of Courtney's Notebooks with Information on Different Crew Members, 1906, 1906 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Courtney's Datebook Recording Weather Conditions, 1906, 1906 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Courtney's Datebook Recording Weather Conditions, 1911, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, June 1972-May 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "For the Game's Sake," by Lawrence Perry, from N.Y. Evening Post, May 17, 1920, May 27, 1920; The article describes a crew race between Cornell, Princeton, and Yale on lake Carnegie. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, March 1971-May 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, January 1971-March 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, May 1967-February 1972, 1967-1972 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, March 1967-February 1972, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, June 1967-August 1972, 1970-1978 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and Assorted Crew Photos, September-October 1947, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1874-1915, 1874-1915 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Ithaca Journal, p. 10, concerning provenance of this collection, May 24, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1900-1958 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Misc. (Box 12, Folder 28)
    Includes copy of the May 29, 1895 Cornell Daily Sun article about the send off the team received on its way to the Henley Regatta. Also a poem about the crew titled "Looking Backward".
  - List of crew members, 1872-1911 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    Includes Freshmen Crew photo in June 4, 1892 Ithaca Daily Journal
  - Courtney journals (Box 15)
    Includes dates 1894, 1903, 1905-1907, 1909, 1922-1924
  - Charles Courtney crew assignments and records, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Charles Courtney crew assignments and records, 1895-1900 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Charles Courtney crew assignments and records, 1904-1907 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Charles Courtney crew assignments and records (contains additional journal entries), 1907 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Charles Courtney crew assignments and records (contains additional journal entries), 1910-1911 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Charles Courtney crew assignments and records, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Charles Courtney crew assignments and records (contains additional journal entries), 1914-1920 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Regatta programs, 1899-1902 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Regatta programs, 1903-1908 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Contains small 1903 "Positions of the crew" card
  - Regatta programs, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Regatta programs, 1913-1916 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    1913 program includes ticket for the observation car on the West Shore Railroad, Poughkeepsie.
  - Regatta programs, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Regatta programs (with press and radio info), 1952 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Regatta programs, 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Henley Royal Regatta programs, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Henley Royal Regatta programs, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Henley Royal Regatta programs, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Poughkeepsie Regatta programs (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Crew celebration programs, 1909-1911, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Class of 1898 banquet program (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Charles Courtney's Rowing Hall of Fame card, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Athletic Association By-laws, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Other programs, 1987, 2003-2004 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - National Association Amateur Oarsmen official guide, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - United States Olympic Trials, Onondaga Lake, Syracuse, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Poughkeepsie New Yorker, photocopies, 1938, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Scrapbook of news clippings, from the Hagar family, 1895-1898 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - "The One That Counted, Heavyweight varsity wins the IRA's" (Cornell Alumni News), 1963 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Stork Sanford death coverage, 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Windermere Cup, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Tickets and Badges, 1956, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    Items from 1956 Potomac regatta and 1957 Henley
  - Packet of material collected by Stephen Rounds, 2011 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - News clippings, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - News clippings, ca. 1950's-1980's (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - "The Last Bastion Falls," Anne Morrissy (New York Herald Tribune), 1954 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - "Big Red Oarsmen Capture IRA Crown", 1971 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Articles on Cornell boathouses, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Crew song, Undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
    Includes a reproduction of an original broadside advertising the song
  - Cornell Freshmen illustration (Harper's Weekly), 1875 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - News clipping regarding intercollegiate regatta on Onondaga Lake, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - "Crew at Cornell", Undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - IRA National Championships, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Rusty Callow's answer to Bruce Lee's question, "Why crew?", Undated (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Misc. boatings and schedules, 1976, Undated (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - "Stroke of Genius", by Alan Maver, Undated (Box 16, Folder 44)
    Galley proof for King Features depicting drawing of Stork Sanford
  - Press release proofs, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - "Intro to sculling, rowing the REC racer," by James H. Dreher, Undated (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Benjamin Evans Dean varsity letter/numerals certificates, 1936-1937 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - "Help The Cornell Navy!...Beecher's Lecture" broadside, Undated (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous items, Undated (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous legal size items, 1950s (Box 16, Folder 50)
    Includes a news letter from Bob Kane about the dedication of the boathouse May 31, 1957 and other crew happenings. Itinerary and program for the 1954 Eastern Sprint Regatta
  - Courtney's personal expense book, 1907 (Box 17)
  - Training table expense book, 1916 (Box 17)
  - Minutes, The Sprague Boat Club of Cornell University, 1 vol., 1874-1901 (Box 17)
  - The Cornell Navy, published vol., 1871-1905 (Box 17)
  - Coach's Creed (Box 18)
  - The Howard M. Smith Cup, background info, 2002 (Box 18)
  - The Raritan Cup, background info, 1994 (Box 18)
  - IRA victory certificates for Robert J. Gabler, Jeffrey B. Granger, and Eric W. Sargent, June 7, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Plans for Women's Boathouse, February 12, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Alumni News articles on John Collyer, 1941, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Articles: Cornell victory in Henley Royal Regatta (1957) and IRA championships on Onondaga Lake (1977), 1957, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Harper's Weekly photo collage of Cornell Crew at Henley Regatta and Harvard-Yale-Cornell boat race at Poughkeepsie, 1897, Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Copies of images from The Daily Graphic, July 1875 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Athletic Hall of Fame posters for Charles E. Courtney, William Seymour Newman, Randolph W. Weed, R. Harrison "Stork" Sanford, and George F. Ford (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Collegiate Crew Board Game (with game cards and pieces), 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook (contains only news clippings), ca. 1895 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Henley Royal Regatta entrance list broadside, 1895 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1955-1956, 1958-1960 (Box 27)
  - Magazine articles about the crew, 1955-1957 (Box 27)
    Includes Sports Illustrated, Time, Life, Presbyterian Life, Rowing, others
  - Newspaper clippings, 1957 (Box 28)
    Includes Henley coverage
  - Henley material, 1892-1895, 1973 (Box MSS 2, Folder 40-1-230m)
    Three photographs of the Cornell Crew at Henley, and six clippings relating to Cornell Crew. Includes a clipping from The Sunday Times (London), July 1, 1973, regarding the Henley Royal Regatta.
  - Harper's Weekly, 1875 (Box MSS 36, Folder 40-1-231m)
    July 24, and 31 1875 issues. Coverage of the Saratoga regatta
  - “Cornell Sweeps College Regatta”, New York Times, photocopy, June 22, 1958 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - 4 Course maps: Ohio River IRA Course (April 1950); the Third Mile, West Shore Course (April 26, 1951); West Shore Course (April 28, 1947); 1 5/16 Mile Course (May 31, 1946), 1940's-1950's (Map-case Folder 6)
  - Photocopy of poster of R. Harrison Sanford with signatures, May 26, 1970 (Map-case Folder 6)
    Given to Sanford at the Cornell Club of New York dinner in his honor
  - "How 'Old Man of Rowing' Won His First Race," New York Herald, April 19, 1914 (Map-case Folder 6)
    Newspaper article about Courtney
  - New York Tribune, May 25, 1913 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - New York Times, July 4, 1915 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - “The Intercollegiate Regatta, Saratoga Lake”, Harper’s Weekly, July 19, 1876 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - “The College Athlete in Doors”, Harper’s Weekly, March 26, 1892 (Map-case Folder 7)
- Series II. Audio and visual material
  - Audio cassette of a 1946 disc recording (Box 7)
  - Video cassette of 1957 crew victory at Henley, V-46
  - Video cassette of 1957 crew victory at Henley, V-301
  - Cornell vs Syracuse Regatta film, May 25, 1929; F-368
    Please use DVD-764, the beginning of the digitized version is cut off, but retained on the original film.
    This film is also available online here: https://media.library.cornell.edu/media/Cornell+vs.+Syracuse+Regatta+1929/1_i6axs14b/5877621
  - The Cornell Crew 1957, 1957; F-1731
    No titles, but may be similar to F-1732
  - The Cornell Crew 1957, 1957; F-1732
    Has titles, but may be similar to F-1731
  - Additional Films (various dates), Film cabinet
    Collyer Boathouse, regattas, etc..
  - Washington, 1926; F-2294 (Box 32)
    16 mm film
  - Henley trip, 1963; F-2292 (Box 32)
  - Ratzeburg EARC sprints, 1963-05-18; F-2293 (Box 32)
  - Sprints Regatta Potomac River, 1956-05-19; F-2304 (Box 33)
  - University of Washington, Long Beach California winning crew, 1933; F-2233 (Box 31)
  - Heavyweight, 1948; F-2274 (Box 32)
    8 mm film
  - Harvard Penn Cornell, 1952; F-2295 (Box 32)
    Outer case reads "1962", reel reads "1952"
  - Varsity, 1961-04-14; F-2175 (Box 29)
  - Varsity, 1961-04-15; F-2176 (Box 29)
  - Port-side varsity and JV, 1962-04; F-2178 (Box 29)
  - Freshman, 1962-06-11; F-2177 (Box 29)
  - JV Syracuse IRA, 1963; F-2179 (Box 29)
  - Varsity Syracuse IRA, 1963; F-2180 (Box 29)
  - Untitled, 1963; F-2234 (Box 31)
  - Fall, 1963-1964; F-2167 (Box 29)
  - Fall, 1963-1964; F-2181 (Box 29)
  - Untitled, 1964; F-2183 (Box 29)
  - Frosh, 1964-04-11; F-2182 (Box 29)
  - Freshman heavyweight, 1964-06-06; F-2174 (Box 29)
  - JV and varsity, 1964-06-08; F-2170 (Box 29)
  - Heavyweight Freshman: Tanks moving water, 1965-02-13; F-2184 (Box 29)
  - Freshman dead water, 1965-02-19; F-2185 (Box 29)
  - Tanks, moving water, 1965-02-27; F-2186 (Box 29)
  - Freshman heavyweight, 1965-04-28; F-2187 (Box 29)
  - All varsity men, 1965-10-19; F-2188 (Box 29)
  - Fall, 1965; F-2190 (Box 29)
  - Fall, 1965-1966; F-2189 (Box 29)
  - Varsity Penn, 1966; F-2191 (Box 29)
  - Freshman MIT and Columbia, 1966; F-2192 (Box 29)
  - JV MIT and Columbia, 1966; F-2193 (Box 29)
  - Varsity MIT, Columbia, 1966; F-2163 (Box 29)
  - Crew Frosh, Penn, 1966; F-2164 (Box 29)
  - Penn., 1966; F-2169 (Box 29)
  - Princeton varsity, 1966; F-2166 (Box 29)
  - JV Penn, 1966; F-2173 (Box 29)
  - Carnegie Cup, 1966; F-2235 (Box 31)
  - Frosh tanks, 1966-02-19; F-2168 (Box 29)
  - Heavyweight freshman, 1966-04-13; F-2194 (Box 29)
  - Freshman, 1966-03-04; F-2198 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1966-05-07; F-2208 (Box 30)
  - Freshman, 1966-05-17; F-2195 (Box 29)
  - Freshman Syracuse IRA, 1966-06-17; F-2196 (Box 29)
  - Varsity at Syracuse, 1966-06-17; F-2197 (Box 30)
  - Syracuse IRA, JV, Frosh 24, 1966-06-17; F-2162 (Box 29)
  - Untitled, 1967; F-2201 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1967; F-2202 (Box 30)
  - HVWT, 1967; F-2203 (Box 30)
  - FRLTWT, 1967; F-2204 (Box 30)
  - Varsity Princeton, 1967; F-2205 (Box 30)
  - Brown, 1967; F-2206 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1967; F-2207 (Box 30)
  - Varsity Crew heavyweight, 1967; F-2161 (Box 29)
  - Heavy Frosh, 1967-03-04; F-2199 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1967-05; F-2238 (Box 31)
  - Frosh, 1967-05-18; F-2200 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1967-07; F-2236 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1967-07; F-2237 (Box 31)
  - Frosh and JV, Penn, 1968; F-2165 (Box 29)
  - Crew, 1968; F-2172 (Box 29)
  - Untitled, 1968; F-2225 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1968; F-2232 (Box 30)
  - Sanford, 1968; F-2239 (Box 31)
  - Third varsity and varsity, 1968; F-2241 (Box 31)
  - Boston ASA 206, 1968-07; F-2242 (Box 31)
  - HVWT, 1968-07; F-2229 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1968-07; F-2230 (Box 30)
  - Freshman in the tanks, 1968-10; F-2240 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1968-10; F-2243 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1969; F-2210 (Box 30)
  - Frosh, 1969; F-2211 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1969; F-2212 (Box 30)
  - LTWT, 1969; F-2213 (Box 30)
  - Frosh versus Dartmouth, 1969; F-2214 (Box 30)
  - Frosh, 1969-04-02; F-2209 (Box 30)
  - HVWT, 1969-06-05; F-2244 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1969-07; F-2245 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1969-08; F-2246 (Box 31)
  - Frosh in tanks, 1969-11-25; F-2247 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1969-11; F-2226 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1969-11; F-2248 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1969-11; F-2249 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1969-11-02-1970; F-2215 (Box 30)
  - Syracuse, 1969-1970; F-2216 (Box 30)
  - Penn race, 1970-04-11; F-2250 (Box 31)
  - Freshman heavyweight, 1970; F-2251 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1970; F-2217 (Box 30)
  - Varsity, 1969-1970; F-2218 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1970; F-2260 (Box 31)
  - Penn race, 1970-04-11; F-2219 (Box 30)
  - Frosh HVWT, 1970; F-2256 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, 1971-07-21; F-2220 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1971; F-2221 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, 1971; F-2222 (Box 30)
  - Syracuse, 1971-10-17; F-2223 (Box 30)
  - Nationals, 1971; F-2224 (Box 30)
  - Practice with Syracuse, 1972-04-14; F-2171 (Box 29)
  - Fall to IRA, 1976-1977; F-2298 (Box 33)
  - 1977-1978 Season, 1977-1978; F-2299 (Box 33)
    Freshman Fall Regatta 1977, Coast Guard Races 1978, Christening of Shells, Princeton Races, EARC, Madiera Cup, IRA
  - Henley and Lucerne, 1977; F-2300 (Box 33)
  - Ellen 5th Womens Regatta, Lake Waramaug, 1979; F-2276 (Box 32)
  - 100' plus x, Undated; F-2227 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2228 (Box 30)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2231 (Box 30)
  - Harvard, Undated; F-2252 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2253 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2254 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2255 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2257 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2258 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2259 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2261 (Box 31)
  - Varsity IRA Champions, training for Henley, Undated; F-2262 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2263 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2264 (Box 31)
  - EARC Sprints and Washington DC, Undated; F-2265 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2266 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2267 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2268 (Box 31)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2269 (Box 32)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2270 (Box 32)
  - Untitled, Undated; F-2271 (Box 32)
  - Some Onondaga, Undated; F-2272 (Box 32)
  - IRA JV ZNA, Undated; F-2273 (Box 32)
  - IRA Onandaga, Undated; F-2275 (Box 32)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2277 (Box 32)
    - Cornell Yale close finish, 1957; F-2278 (Box 32)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2279 (Box 32)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2280 (Box 32)
    - IRA FR SBRA, Undated; F-2281 (Box 32)
    - Johnson-Hough, Harvard-Penn, Ron and Ann's wedding, 1968; F-2282 (Box 32)
    - Harvard HV, 1974; F-2283 (Box 32)
    - JV Varsity Florida, 1968; F-2284 (Box 32)
    - Mandie's diploma, Johnson-Hough, Undated; F-2285 (Box 32)
    - Florida, 1968; F-2286 (Box 32)
    - Princeton, EARC, Seward PRR, 1957-05-18; F-2287 (Box 32)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2288 (Box 32)
    - Varsity, 1957; F-2289 (Box 32)
    - Test Roll II, Undated; F-2290 (Box 32)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2291 (Box 32)
    - Victory at Henley, Undated; F-2296 (Box 33)
    - Memories of Cornell Crew, Undated; F-2297 (Box 33)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2301 (Box 33)
      1/2" film
    - Larkin breathing, balance, stretching, Undated; F-2302 (Box 33)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2303 (Box 33)
    - Films of the Cornell Crew, Undated; V-11001 (Box 33)
      VHS
- Series III. Photographs
  - Black and white prints plus a few negatives, most with identification by Courtney; Courtney home and other Union Springs, N.Y. locations, views of Ithaca from 218 Eddy Street and from Cayuga Inlet, pictures of crews, mostly taken at Ithaca, Poughkeepsie, and Henley (Box 2-4)
  - 3 1/4" x 4" black and white slides in wood boxes (Box 5-6)
  - Photograph album, ca. 1890 (Box 7)
  - Slides (Box 10)
  - Photo of 1873 Crew, 1873 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Photo of Crew Varsity, 1876, 1876 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photos of Courtney and Crew at Poughkeepsie, 1896, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Photos of Freshman and Varsity Crew, 1897, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Group Photo of Varsity Crew, 1897, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Varsity Crew Photos on Cayuga Lake, 1899-1900, 1899-1900 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Group Photo of Varsity Crew, 1902, 1902 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Varsity Crew Photos from 1903 and 1911, 1903, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Photo of Varsity Crew 1905 and Photo of Snow in Poughkeepsie, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Photos of Varsity Crew 1909 and 1911, 1909, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Photo of Freshman Crew 1911 and Photo of Poughkeepsie, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Photo of Courtney with Crew Candidates (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Photo of Varsity Crew, 1897, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Photo of Crew, 1930, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Photo Negatives Displaying Sailing Boats (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Article Excerpt with Freshman and Varsity Crew Photos, 1875, 1875 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Photo of Crew Practice, 1892, 1892 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Photo of Varsity Crew Practicing at Poughkeepsie, 1897, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Photo of Crew Practice, 1903, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Photo of Varsity Crew, 1905, 1905 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Photo of Freshman Crew at Poughkeepsie, June 1907, June 1907 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Photo of Varsity Crew at Poughkeepsie, June 1907, June 1907 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Crew, 1910-1911, 1910-1911 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Undated Crew Photo (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Undated Photos Displaying Several Crew Boats on a Lake (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Original Paper Overlays and Mounting for Crew Photos (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Original Paper Overlay and Mounting for Crew Photo (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Photo of Crew Boat Beside Cayuga Breakwater Lighthouse (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Photo of the Poughkeepsie Railroad Bridge with Several Boats Beneath (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Photo of Crew, 1891, 1891 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Photo of Crew Boats in Poughkeepsie, July 1915, July 1915 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Varsity crew (2 copies), 1937 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - W.S. [Bill] Newman portrait, ca. 1900's (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Enlarged portrait of William H. Forbes, ca. 1900's (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Portrait of Albert W. Smith, Undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Photo of Freshman Crew 1899, Winners at Poughkeepsie, N.Y. on June 241 1896 Over Harvard, Pennsylvania, and Columbia, 1896, 1899 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Photo of Edwin Regur Sweetland, Varsity Crew, Presented by the Phi Gamma Delta Fraternity, 1899, 1899 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Photo of Robert L. Shape, '95 Freshman Crew, Presented by the Beta Theta Pi Fraternity (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Henry E. Vanderhoef, Captain of Varsity 1901 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1981 IRA champions poster (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1982 IRA champions poster (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1913-14 Varsity Eight photo, 1913-1914 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1901 Varsity group photo (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1902 Varsity group photo (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Photo collage with signatures and messages, ca. 1970's (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Team Photos 1939 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Includes Freshman and Varsity crew
  - Team Photos 1940's (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Includes Lightweight, Varsity and Eastern Sprint Champions
  - Team Photos 1950's, 1952-1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Includes Henley Royal Regatta, Harvard record, Junior Varsity, Lightweight, Varsity and IRA Champions
  - Team Photos 1960's, 1960-1968 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Includes Lightweight Varsity, Lightweight, Tri-champions Eastern Sprint Regatta and Heavyweight
  - Team Photos 1970's (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Includes Lightweight, Varsity and IRA Champions
  - Team Photos 1980's, 1981-1989 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Includes Freshman A and B teams, Lightweight, Heavyweight, Varsity, Men's 4 boat, and Sprints
  - Cabinet cards of Crew team, including Charles Courtney, circa 1890 (Box 18)